

# DANIEL ANDRES SIMANGUNSONG

I am an information system student who is interested in website development. Fast learner and enthusiastic about learning new things, especially in software engineering. A team worker and willing to be led by experienced developers.

# **Work Experiences**

#### Startup Campus - MSIB - Indonesia

Feb 2023 - Present

#### Data Science Learning Path

Currently enrolled in a 5 month Data Science course led by a professional technology instructor. This course covers Statistics, analysis, data wrangling, data visualization, deep working with SQL & python tools, and machine learning on structured data.

### Del Institute of Technology - Sitoluama, Indonesia

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

### Student Teaching Assistant Visual Programming

Assist and teach student on the practicum schedule. Assisted instructor with in-class activities by grading assignments, tutoring and proctoring examinations.

### Del Institute of Technology - Sitoluama, Indonesia

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

### Student Teaching Assistant Algorithms and Data Structures

Assist and teach student on the practicum schedule.

#### **Education Level**

### Institut Teknologi Del - Sitoluama, Indonesia

Sep 2020 - Sep 2024 (Expected)

Bachelor Degree in Information Systems, 3.40/4.00

# Organisational Experience

### Del Programming Club - Sitoluama, Indonesia

May 2022 - Present

### Core Coding Team

Practice solving algorithm/logic problems given by the supervisor to take part in the competition.

### BEM of Del Institute of Technolog - Sitoluama, Indonesia

Apr 2021 - Present

### Member of Department Of Information And Communication

Documenting important campus events and organizing and disseminating documentation artifacts.

### Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Informasi (HIMSI) - Sitoluama, Indonesia

Feb 2021 - Present

### Member

Helping Lecture Activities such as providing lecture resources and tutorials.

### Del Cyber Security Club - Sitoluama, Indonesia

Oct 2020 - Present

#### Member

Holding webinars with expert speakers and conducting discussions among team members to prepare for the competition.

## Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Achievements (2021): Member of Finalist Team National IT Student Show (GEMASTIK), created a proposal regarding hoax detection based on sentence structure and diction selection
- **Projects** (2022): Web Application Programming and Testing Project (Del Clinic), Collaborate in a team to develop a website that controls patient data and assets at the Del Institute of Technology clinic. This website is built using Laravel framework and SQL database.
- **Projects** (2023): Powe Human Project, Develop a website that controls / manages a company such as controlling employees and their responsibilities.. This website is built using the Laravel framework, Nuxt Js and MySQL database.
- **Projects** (2022): Artificial Intelligence Project(Attendance Tracking Based On Face Recognition), built using the python programming language with the Computational thinking (CT) method.
- Hard Skills: Laravel, Python, Java, OOP, REST APIs, PHP, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, UI/UX, SDLC, Canva
- Soft Skills: Communication Skills, Teamwork, Time Management, Analytical